getnymi.com 2019-07-22

# Privacy Policy | Nymi

## NYMI PRIVACY POLICY

If you are visiting from the EU see our GDPR Privacy Policy.

Click here to view our Cookie Policy.

### Last Updated: August 2016

Nymi Inc. and its divisions, affiliates and subsidiaries (hereinafter "Nymi") respects the privacy and the integrity of any information that is collected through our Web sites, the provision of our products and/or services, or that you otherwise provide to us. This Privacy Policy explains our policy regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of your personal information.

This Privacy Policy will be assessed against new technologies, business practices, and our users' needs. As we update, expand, and diversify our products and services, this Privacy Policy may evolve. Please check this Privacy Policy from time to time for updates by checking the date of the "Last Update" at the top of this document. If we make any material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you here. A link to our Privacy Policy will be provided at the bottom of each web page on our Web sites and any on-line services or programs.

You acknowledge and agree that your access to our Web sites and your use of our products and/or services following any posted changes to the Privacy Policy indicate your acceptance of such changes.

### Application of this policy

At Nymi, we are committed to protecting the privacy of our users, which is why we do not sell nor rent any personal information or personally identifiable information regarding our users to any third party. We hope this Privacy Policy will answer your questions regarding how we treat personal information gathered from visitors to our Web sites and users of our products and/or services.

### What is personal information

For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, personal information means information that can be used to identify or contact you, such as your name, address, email address, country of residence, as well as other information when such information is combined with your personal information. Personal information does not include "aggregate" anonymous information that does not identify an individual person, which is data we collect about the use of our Web sites and our products and services. Our privacy policy does not restrict or limit our collection and use of aggregate, anonymous information.

### Consent

You acknowledge and agree that by accessing our Web sites or using our products and/or services, or otherwise providing us with personal information, you fully understand, accept, and voluntarily consent to the collection, use, retention, and disclosure of personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with any terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use our Web sites, products or services nor submit any personal information to Nymi. It is your choice whether or not you provide us with your personal information; however, a decision to withhold personal information may restrict or prevent us from providing you with a particular product or service. We will only collect, use, and disclose your personal information with your consent, except where otherwise permitted or required by applicable law or regulatory requirement.

### Collection of personal information

Should you choose to place an order for products or services, you will need to provide payment information such as credit card numbers, billing addresses and your IP address to our trusted third party service provider. Credit card information, including the card number, expiry date, and security code, is securely collected by our trusted third party service provider. Credit card data is not viewed nor retained by Nymi in any form.

### Use of your personal information

You acknowledge and agree that Nymi may use personal information that you voluntarily disclose to us to:

  1. Provide you with information about new products, services, newsletters, informative emails, and research on future product ideas or improvements, where you have agreed to receive such materials;

  2. Provide you with special offers that may be of interest to you and to improve your experience on our Web sites or with our products and services;

  3. Assist us in creating better products and services to meet your needs;

  4. Allow you to purchase and download products, obtain access to services or otherwise engage in activities you select including but not limited to the Nymi Band product;

  5. Provide you with technical support;

  6. Help you quickly find software, services, or product information important to you;

  7. Send transaction-related communications such as welcome letters and product/service order confirmations. Nymi may also send you surveys or marketing communications to inform you of new products or services or other information that may be of interest;

  8. Restrict the availability of some of the products, services, and content to certain parts of the world, where required for legal reasons, by using your address, IP address, and other information in order to enforce those restrictions;

  9. To carry out other purposes that are disclosed to you and to which you consent; and

  10. To carry out any other purpose permitted or required by law.

The Nymi Band allows you to use biometric authentication technology [such as a template of your heart's unique ECG] to confirm your identity and allow you to access devices and services you choose to associate with the Nymi Band using the Nymi Band app. When you use the Nymi Band, an encrypted replica of your ECG signature is recorded and wirelessly transmitted to the device on which you have installed the Nymi Band app, allowing the device to confirm your identity. However, it is important to note that Nymi does not and cannot itself collect, use, view, or have access to your ECG template when you use the Nymi Band and Nymi Band app. Your ECG template is stored in an encrypted state within the Nymi Band and not transmitted to Nymi.

You agree that you are under no obligation to provide us with this information and can access many aspects of our Web sites without providing us any personal information.

While using the Web site, you may have opportunities to post reviews or other personal information in public forums at your own discretion. Please understand that when you post such information, it is public and Nymi is not able to protect it from other persons who may view the public areas of our Web site. You should exercise caution when deciding to disclose any personal information in a publicly available forum such as the Web site and agree to release, indemnify, and hold harmless Nymi for any damages or claims resulting from any of your postings. Nymi is not obligated to monitor postings and at its discretion may remove any content submitted.

### Disclosure of your personal information

Except as otherwise disclosed to you or required or permitted by applicable law, Nymi will not sell nor rent your personal information to any other party. Nymi will only use and disclose your personal information for the purposes for which it was collected as described in this Privacy Policy. However, you agree that Nymi may disclose your personal information in the circumstances set out below:

  1. Nymi may disclose your personal information with your prior consent;

  2. Nymi may be required by law to disclose personal information without your knowledge or consent in the event of emergency situations or when required by government or other legal authority;

  3. Nymi may also disclose personal information to third parties in connection with a corporate re-organization, merger or amalgamation, or the sale of all or substantially all of its assets, provided that, where appropriate, any party to whom the information is disclosed is bound by agreements or obligations, and required to use or disclose your personal information in a manner consistent with the use and disclosure provisions of this Privacy Policy, unless you consent otherwise;

  4. Nymi may also use, or disclose your personal information to third parties, if we have reason to believe that using or disclosing such information is necessary to: (i) conduct investigations of possible breaches of law; (ii) identify, contact, or bring legal action against someone who may be violating an agreement they have with us; (iii) investigate security breaches or cooperate with government authorities pursuant to a legal matter or (iv) to protect our rights, safety or property; or

  5. Nymi may share your personal information with service providers who perform services on our behalf. For example, we may hire other companies to handle the processing of payments, collect debts, to provide data storage, to host websites, to fulfill orders, to assist in direct marketing, to conduct audits, etc. Those companies will be permitted to obtain only the personal information they need to provide the service. Each company is bound by agreement or obligations with Nymi to implement and maintain reasonable security procedures and practices in order to use and disclose your personal information in a manner consistent with the use and disclosure provisions of this Privacy Policy, unless you consent otherwise.

### How to opt-out / withdraw consent

Subject to legal and contractual obligations where applicable, you can withdraw your consent for the use of your personal information you have provided to us, you should do so either through links provided in communications to you or by visiting forums.nymi.com and selecting ‘preferences’. You must be signed in to access your ‘preferences’.

Information may be retained by Nymi for audit or archival purposes or as required by applicable federal and provincial laws.

If you do not wish to receive marketing communications, you may follow the "unsubscribe" instructions included within each email communication or by selecting or deselecting (depending on the service) the appropriate option through links provided in communications to you. Please keep in mind that, even if you choose not to receive marketing communications, you may continue to receive transactional or account communications related to services or products that you have requested (e.g. purchase confirmation emails and receipts).

### How long we keep personal information

Nymi maintains information about you for as long as we provide a product and/or service to you, and longer for related business activities. After information is no longer necessary for our business purposes, we destroy the information unless there is an outstanding request or order to preserve the information.

### Safeguards we have in place

Nymi stores and processes your personal information on computers located in Canada and in the cloud internationally. Nymi employs reasonable physical, organizational, managerial and technical measures to help ensure that your personal information is secure. In addition, our dedicated team of information technology professionals works to maintain data accuracy and help prevent unauthorized access to sensitive information. Personal information may only be accessed by persons within our organization, or our third party service providers, who require such access to carry out the purposes indicated above.

Unfortunately, no security system can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Accordingly, we cannot guarantee the security of your personal information and cannot assume liability for improper access to it. The Internet is not a secure medium and you acknowledge and agree that the privacy of your email communication and personal information can never be guaranteed as any email communication may be lost, intercepted or altered. By using our Web sites, or providing personal information to us through any means, you agree that we may communicate with you electronically regarding security, privacy, and administrative issues relating to your use of our Web sites and our services.

Some or all of the personal information we collect may be stored or processed on servers located outside your jurisdiction of residence, including in the United States, whose data protection laws may differ from the jurisdiction in which you live. As a result, this information may be subject to access requests from governments, courts, or law enforcement in those jurisdictions according to laws in those jurisdictions. Subject to applicable laws in such other jurisdictions, we will use reasonable efforts to ensure that appropriate protections are in place to require the data processor in that country to maintain protections on the personal information.

### Children

This Web site, products and services are not intended for use by children, especially those under age 13. No one under age 13 is allowed to register for the products or services, provide any personally identifiable information or use our social, community and public discussion areas, photo and video galleries, bulletin boards, forums, chats, blogs, personal/job search and other classified ads, and elsewhere. Minors between the ages of 13 and 17 or 18, inclusive, must get the permission of their parent(s) or legal guardian(s) before making purchases, including subscriptions.

### Accessing and correcting your personal information

You are responsible for updating and maintaining the truth and accuracy of the personal information you provide to us. If you want to update the personal information you have provided to us, you should do so either through links provided in communications to you or by visiting forums.nymi.com and selecting ‘preferences’. You must be signed in to access your ‘preferences’.

You can also ask to see your personal information or request a correction to it if you believe it is inaccurate. If you want to review, verify or correct your personal information, please contact our Privacy Officer using the contact information provided below. Please note that any such communication must be in writing. Generally, your information is kept at our corporate offices in Toronto, Canada (see address information below).

When requesting access to your personal information, please note that we may request specific information from you to enable us to confirm your identity and right to access, as well as to search for and provide you with the personal information that we hold about you. If you require assistance in preparing your request, please contact the office of our Privacy Officer.

Your right to access the personal information that we hold about you is not absolute. There are instances where applicable law or regulatory requirements allow or require us to refuse to provide some or all of the personal information that we hold about you. In addition, the personal information may have been destroyed, erased or made anonymous in accordance with our record retention obligations and practices.

In the event that we cannot provide you with access to your personal information, we will endeavor to inform you of the reasons why, subject to any legal or regulatory restrictions.

### Collection of non-personal information

You acknowledge and agree that from time to time Nymi, its service providers and business partners may collect non-personal information from your use of our Web site and services such as server log files, environmental variables (such as computer type (Windows or Macintosh), screen resolution, OS version, Internet browser, Internet browser version) and from scanning navigational data to collect non-personal information about our users in order to help us deliver better service and user experience. Such non-personal information could include the IP addresses or areas of site being clicked on most frequently.

Nymi and its service providers (including ad servers, outbound email vendors, affiliate vendors and search engine advertising agencies, and providers of web analytics tools) and business partners may also use "cookies" as well as so-called "pixel tags," "web beacons," "clear GIFs" and other similar technologies to help deliver better service and user experience as well as to facilitate your ongoing access to and use of our products and services. Cookies are files saved to your computers through your Web browser to enable websites or service providers’ systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. Nymi, like many other Web services, uses cookies to understand and save your preferences for future visits and to compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction, so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future. If you do not want information collected through the use of cookies, there is a simple procedure in most browsers that allows you to automatically decline cookies, or to be given the choice of declining or accepting the transfer of a particular cookie, or cookies from a particular website, to your computer. If you choose to reject all cookies, you may not be able to access some of our services. To learn more about cookies, please visit <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/>. You may find more information about opting out of many third-party service cookies at [www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) or other related sites.

### Hyperlinks

Our Web sites are connected by "hyperlinks" to other websites. You acknowledge and agree that Nymi makes no representation, warranty, covenant, or claim regarding, and Nymi expressly disclaims and denies any responsibility or liability for, directly or indirectly, the privacy practices on any third-party website or resource accessible by hyperlink from our Web sites. You agree that the inclusion of any such hyperlink does not suggest, represent, warrant, covenant or imply that Nymi monitors, endorses or exerts any control over such website or linked resource whatsoever. You agree that Nymi provides these hyperlinks to you only as a convenience, and the inclusion of any hyperlink does not suggest, represent, warrant, covenant or imply affiliation, endorsement or adoption by Nymi of any such website or linked resource whatsoever.

When you leave our Web sites, you acknowledge and agree that our terms and policies do not govern your access to, and use of, other websites. You acknowledge our recommendation to review the applicable privacy and data gathering practices, of any website or linked resource to which you navigate from our Web sites.

### Third Party Service Providers

Nymi may use one or more third party service providers as the payment processor for its products and services. When you choose to make a purchase or make a transaction, you disclose personal information to these third party service providers such as your name, email address and credit card information so that these third party service providers may process your transaction.

You acknowledge and agree that Nymi makes no representation, warranty, covenant, or claim regarding, and Nymi expressly disclaims and denies any responsibility or liability for, directly or indirectly, the privacy practices in regard to any personal information you provide to any third party service provider directly or any other party in relation to purchasing a Nymi product or service.

You acknowledge and agree that our terms and policies do not govern any other party.

You acknowledge our recommendation to review the applicable privacy and data gathering practices, of any third party to which you provide personal information.

### Interpretation of this Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy does not create or confer upon any individual any rights, or impose upon Nymi any obligations, in addition to any rights or obligations imposed by Canada's applicable federal and provincial privacy laws. Should there be any inconsistency between this Privacy Policy and Canada's applicable federal and provincial privacy laws, this Privacy Policy will be interpreted in a manner that complies with the applicable privacy laws.

Any Web site and/or products and services provided by Nymi are controlled and managed by us from Canada, and we do not intend that our services subject us to the laws or jurisdiction of any state, country or territory other than that of Canada. We do not represent or warrant that the Web site and/or products and services, or any part of the Web site and/or products and services, are appropriate or available for use in any particular jurisdiction. Those who choose to access the Web site and/or products and services do so on their own initiative and at their own risk, and are responsible for complying with all local laws, rules and regulations. We may limit the Web site and/or products and services availability, in whole or in part, to any person, geographic area or jurisdiction we choose, at any time and in our sole discretion.

**Inquiries or Concerns?**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or have any concerns about how we manage your personal information, please contact our Privacy Officer by telephone, in writing or by email. We will endeavor to answer your questions and advise you of any steps taken to address the issues raised by you. If you are dissatisfied with our response, you may be entitled to make a written submission to the Privacy Commissioner in your jurisdiction.

**Privacy Officer**

We have appointed a Privacy Officer to oversee compliance with this Privacy Policy.

The contact information for our Privacy Officer is as follows:

Attention: Privacy Officer  
82 Peter Street, Suite 500, Toronto, ON, Canada  
Phone: 1 416 977 3042  
Email: [info@nymi.com](mailto:info@nymi.com)
